CHRIS NMASICHI FAVOUR NYECHE

Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria. nyechechris@gmail.com | 09036640844 26th February in www.linkedin.com/in/chris-nyeche



OBJECTIVE

I am Meticulous Frontend web developer with over 3 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Implemented new responsive website approach which increased mobile traffic by 20%. Ready to work remotely and Hybrid.

EDUCATION

IMO STATE UNIVERSITY Bachelor Of Science (BSc.)	2011 - 2015
CODELIBER DATA SCIENCE ONLINE SCHOOL	2020 - 2022
Front End Development	1010 1011
5.0	
DEVTOWN ONLINE SCHOOL	2021 - 2022
Front End Development Boot	
SIMPLILEARN DEVELOPMENT SCHOOL	2021 - Date
Javascript Mastery	
ALX ENGINEERING SCHOOL	2022
Full Stack Developer	
APP ACADEMY	2022
Software Engineering	
LINKEDIN MICROSOFT	2022
Junior Wordpress Developer	

EXPERIENCE

Devtown Online Academy
2019 - 2022

Frontend Developer

Optimizing the user experience.

Using HTML, JavaScript and CSS to bring concepts to life.

Developing and maintaining the user interface.

Implementing design on mobile websites.

Creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the browser.

Managing software workflow

• Tech Creek 2021 - 2022

Internship

Optimizing the user experience.

Using HTML, JavaScript and CSS to bring concepts to life.

Developing and maintaining the user interface.

Implementing design on mobile websites.

Creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the browser.

Managing software workflow

• Cinfores Limited 2021 - Date

Frontend Developer/Data Administrator

Developing new user-facing features Determining the structure and design of web pages.

Building reusable codes.

Optimizing page loading times.

Using a variety of latest Frontend stacks and languages to create the web pages.

• Chris Designs 2022

Web Developer/Frontend Enginer

User interface page building

Web testing and Analysis

Team collaboration and development of assigned project structures.

SKILLS

· Graphic and User Interface Development

- Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Wordpress Engineering
- Verbal and Written Communication
- Web Components Development
- Bug Resolution
- · Project Scoping and Production Worm
- Website Maintenance
- · End user training
- User Research and Analysis

PROJECTS

Blue Weather App

Blue Weather app is a friendly night and day app that displays weather and shows the weather location background.

• Gatehouse Web Application

Gatehouse project is a project that enables strategic monitoring of visitors in a company, organization and firm.

Afroblogg

A blogging site that showcases the wonders of Africa and the beauty of the African continent, art and structure to the rest of the world.

• Designoper

A platform were web designers and developers can collaborate as teams to build applications and solve societal problems.

INTERESTS

- Tourism
- Politics
- Networking
- Sports
- Application Development
- Inspirational Books

LANGUAGE

- English Language
- Igbo

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

• DevTown Best Supporter

ABOUT ME

Core Values

I am very:

*****Creative

*Humble

*Responsible

*****Innovative

Simple

Signature:

Chris Nmasichi Favour Nyeche